{
  "title": "General_Aptitude-_CSE - General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 14 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 14",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>The value of \\(\\sqrt{12+\\sqrt{12+\\sqrt{12+\\dots}}}\\) is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>3.464</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3.932</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4.444</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>4</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1942/gate-cse-2014-set-2-question-ga-5#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>What is the average of all multiples of 10 from 2 to 198? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>90</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>100</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>110</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>120</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>100</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1941/gate-cse-2014-set-2-question-ga-4#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Match the columns.\n<br><br>\\(\\begin{array}{ll|ll}\\hline &amp;\\textbf{Column 1} &amp; &amp; \\textbf{Column 2 } \\\\\\hline 1.&amp; \\text{eradicate} &amp;P. &amp;\\text{misrepresent}\\\\\\hline 2.&amp;\\text{distort} &amp;Q.&amp; \\text{soak completely}\\\\\\hline 3.&amp;\\text{saturate} &amp;R.&amp; \\text{use}\\\\\\hline 4.&amp;\\text{utilize} &amp;S.&amp; \\text{destroy utterly}\\\\\\hline \\end{array}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1:S, 2:P, 3:Q, 4:R</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1:P, 2:Q, 3:R, 4:S</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1:Q, 2:R, 3:S, 4:P</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1:S, 2:P, 3:R, 4:Q</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>1:S, 2:P, 3:Q, 4:R</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1940/gate-cse-2014-set-2-question-ga-3#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Who ___________ was coming to see us this evening? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>you said</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>did you say</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>did you say that</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>had you said</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>did you say</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1939/gate-cse-2014-set-2-question-ga-2#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate phrase from the options given below to complete the following sentence.\n<br><br>\nIndia is a post-colonial country because <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>it was a former British colony</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Indian Information Technology professionals have colonized the world</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>India does not follow any colonial practices</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>India has helped other countries gain freedom</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>it was a former British colony</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1938/gate-cse-2014-set-2-question-ga-1#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>When a point inside of a tetrahedron (a solid with four triangular surfaces) is connected by straight lines to its corners, how many (new) internal planes are created with these lines? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "6",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/778/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-10#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>In a survey, 300 respondents were asked whether they own a vehicle or not. If yes, they were further asked to mention whether they own a car or scooter or both. Their responses are tabulated below. What percent of respondents do not own a scooter?<br><br>\\(\\begin{array}{|l|l|l|l|} \\hline &amp; &amp; \\text{Men} &amp; \\text{Women} \\\\\\hline \\text{Own vehicle} &amp; \\text{Car} &amp; 40 &amp; 34 \\\\\\hline \\text{Own vehicle} &amp; \\text{Scooter} &amp; 30 &amp; 20 \\\\\\hline \\text{Own vehicle} &amp; \\text{Both} &amp; 60 &amp; 46 \\\\\\hline \\text{Do not own vehicle} &amp; &amp; 20 &amp; 50 \\\\\\hline \\end{array}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "48",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/777/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-9#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Round-trip tickets to a tourist destination are eligible for a discount of 10% on the total fare. In addition, groups of 4 or more get a discount of 5% on the total fare. If the one way single person fare is Rs 100, a group of 5 tourists purchasing round-trip tickets will be charged Rs __________ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "850",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/776/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-8#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Geneticists say that they are very close to confirming the genetic roots of psychiatric illnesses such as depression and schizophrenia, and consequently, that doctors will be able to eradicate these diseases through early identification and gene therapy.\n<br><br>\nOn which of the following assumptions does the statement above rely?\n<br>\nSelect one: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Strategies are now available for eliminating psychiatric illnesses</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Certain psychiatric illnesses have a genetic basis</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>All human diseases can be traced back to genes and how they are expressed</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>In the future, genetics will become the only relevant field for identifying psychiatric illnesses</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Certain psychiatric illnesses have a genetic basis</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/775/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-7#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>The Palghat Gap (or Palakkad Gap) , a region about 30 km wide in the southern part of the Western Ghats in India, is lower than the hilly terrain to its north and south. The exact reasons for the formation of this gap are not clear. It results in the neighbouring regions of Tamil Nadu getting more rainfall from the South West monsoon and the neighbouring regions of Kerala having higher summer temperatures.\n<br><br>\nWhat can be inferred from this passage?\n<br>\nSelect one: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The Palghat gap is caused by high rainfall and high temperatures in southern Tamil Nadu and Kerala</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The regions in Tamil Nadu and Kerala that are near the Palghat Gap are low-lying</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The low terrain of the Palghat Gap has a significant impact on weather patterns in neighbouring parts of Tamil Nadu and Kerala</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Higher summer temperatures result in higher rainfall near the Palghat Gap area</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>The low terrain of the Palghat Gap has a significant impact on weather patterns in neighbouring parts of Tamil Nadu and Kerala</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/774/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-6#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The roots of \\(ax^2+bx+c=0\\) are real and positive.  \\(a,b \\text{ and } c\\) are real. Then \\(ax^2+b|x|+c=0\\) has <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>no roots</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2 real roots</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>3 real roots</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4 real roots</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>4 real roots</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/770/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-5#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>If \\(\\left(z + \\dfrac{1}{z}\\right)^{2}= 98\\), compute \\(\\left(z^2 + \\dfrac{1}{z^2}\\right)\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "96",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/773/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-4#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>In a press meet on the recent scam, the minister said, \"The buck stops here\". What did the minister convey by the statement? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>He wants all the money</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>He will return the money</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>He will assume final responsibility</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>He will resist all enquiries</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>He will assume final responsibility</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/772/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-3#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence.\n<br><br>\nHe could not understand the judges awarding her the first prize, because he thought that her performance was quite _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>superb</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>medium</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>mediocre</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>exhilarating</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>mediocre</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/771/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-2#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following options is the closest in meaning to the phrase in bold in the\nsentence below?<br><br>It is fascinating to see life forms **cope with** varied environmental conditions. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Adopt to</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Adapt to</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Adept in</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Accept with</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Adapt to</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/56/gate-cse-2014-set-1-question-ga-1#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}